<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cloud | Metaphor]]></title>
  <link href="http://metaphor.github.io/blog/categories/cloud/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://metaphor.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-18T14:11:23+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://metaphor.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Zhiheng Li]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[VirtualBox network adapter]]></title>
    <link href="http://metaphor.github.io/blog/2013/02/06/virtualbox-network-adapter-explained/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-06T21:27:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://metaphor.github.io/blog/2013/02/06/virtualbox-network-adapter-explained</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A network adatper is the way for your virtual machine instances to connect
outside world, rather working as a standalone node.</p>

<h3>VirtualBox has 4 types of network adapters</h3>

<p><a href="https://www.virtualbox.org">VirtualBox</a> has basically 4 types of network adapters, provding
comprehensive means to build your network topology.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h4>NAT (Network Address Transform)</h4>

<p>With this adpater, the virtual instance can access the outside world by
forwarding the request to host, and the host might re-farword the
response back to the virtual instance. The forwarding rules could be
configured.</p>

<p>The disadvantage is that the outside world knows only the host, rather the
viratual instance. This means you cannot access the instance directly.</p>

<h4>Bridged</h4>

<p>Bridged adapter might be the easiest and most user friendly. It makes
the virtual instance a new physical node like in your network environment, separating
from the host. It could obtain IP address from DHCP server.</p>

<p>Such ease leads to an inconvience, your instance network configuration
changes as long as your host network environment changes. That means
each time you need a different IP to connect to the instance.</p>

<h4>Internal Network</h4>

<p>This adapter usually uses static IP and only allows virtual instance to communicate with other
instances generated by the same VirtualBox. This result in that even
the host cannot access the instance. Of course, the instance has no
Internet access.</p>

<h4>Host Only</h4>

<p>This is my favorite adpater, it combines advantages both of Bridged
and Internal Network. Virtual instances and host can commnunicate with
each other without any problem. But the instance cannot connect
the Internet, because it does not connect to the network environment
of the host.</p>

<p>To configure Host only adapter, you need to set up a host only
network first. On Mac OS, goes to <code>Preferences &ndash;> Network &ndash;> Add(Host
only network)</code></p>

<h3>How to choose right adapters</h3>

<p>Each adapter has its own limitations, so the best solution is to configure
those adapters in a combined way. VirtualBox allows you to configure multiple adpaters
within same instances. Also different use cases have their own
combinations.</p>

<h4>Instances within same host</h4>

<p>Sometimes your instances would be created only in the same host, eg,
experimental cluster on you laptop. In this case, I would like to combine,</p>

<ul>
<li>NAT</li>
<li>Host-only</li>
</ul>


<p>This combination allows the virtual instances to access Internet. The
host and virtual instances can consistently communicate with each other over static
IP.</p>

<h4>Instances acrossing hosts</h4>

<p>In real world, there is no such experiment, if you want to leverage
the VirtualBox for your infrastructure, you probly need to start new
instances across different hosts. In this case, it requires the
commnunication between instances across hosts. The host only adapter might not
fit in this case, so I would like to use,</p>

<ul>
<li>Bridged</li>
<li>Switch infrastructure</li>
</ul>


<p>Bridged instance connect to your network infrastructure via switch, working as
new physical machine. Basically, this allow virtual instances to access the Internet as
well if your network infrastructure allows.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
